外科医生的生活总是一团糟
Surgeons are all messed up.
我们是屠夫  日子一团糟  却又嗜刀
We're butchers, messed-up knife-happy butchers.
先生  要在她病房给你准备张卡片吗
Sir, would you like a card set up for you in her room?
我们在病人身上动刀  我们接着活下去
We cut people up. We move on.
看着我们的病人死去  我们照样活下去
Patients die on our watch. We move on.
不用  我是这里的医生
No. I'm a doctor here.
我们造成伤痛  也忍受伤痛
We cause trauma. We suffer trauma.
等等
Wait.
就是这里
And here it comes.
我们无暇担心流血  死亡
We don't have time to worry about how all the blood, and death,
各种琐事会如何影响我们
and crap really makes us feel.
就该这样一边喝着小酒
This is how you went wine
一边连看两小时的高级冠状动脉手术
By watching two hours straight advanced coronary artery.
克里斯蒂娜
Christina?
没事吧
Everything OK?
克里斯蒂娜  欧文
Christina! Owen!
凌晨三点
Three in the morning.
克里斯蒂娜  最好是要紧事
Christina, this better be good...
凯丽
Callie.
什么  他做了什么
What? He what?
是我  克里斯蒂娜
It's me. Christina.
出什么事了
What's going on?
欧文一脸沮丧  凯丽惊声把我叫来
Owen's out there upset. Callie was screaming.
视敏度没问题
没有淤斑
No petechia
我没事
I'm fine.
-我没事  没事  没事  -天哪  你的脖子
- I'm Fine, I'm fine, I'm fine. - Oh, my god. your neck!
-我去宰了他  -不要
- I will kill him. - No.
只是噩梦  他做噩梦来着
It was a nightmare. He had a nightmare.
克里斯蒂娜  开开门吧
Christina, please.
她没事吧  我想知道她有没有事
She all right? I just need to know if She is all right.
不能开
No. No. No. No.
克里斯蒂娜  不许开
Christina. No.
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我不知道我怎么了  我
I don't know what happened. I'm ...
我不知道我怎么了
I don't know what happened.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-看着我  -对不起 我...
- Look at me. - I'm sorry I...
看着我
Look at me.
我没事
I'm fine.
看见没  我没事的
See? It's OK.
你当时睡着了  没事的  听见没
You were asleep. It's OK. OK?
没事了  没事了
It's OK. It's OK.
-对不起  -没事  我知道的
- I'm sorry. - It's OK. I know.
没事  你当时睡着了  没事了
It's OK. You were asleep. It's OK...
没事了
It's OK.
没事了  没事了
It's OK. It's OK.
咖啡来了
Here's coffee.
别这样  我不喜欢这样
No. I don't like this.
今天是你回医院的第一天
Today is your first day back to the hospital.
今天  伊兹才是重点
Today is about Izzie.
你得给她做脑手术
You have to operate on her brain.
你有天赋
You have a gift.
你行的
And you can do this.
出发前我先洗个澡
I'll get a shower before I go there.
德瑞克 你回来了
Derek, you back
感谢上帝 你回来了
Thank God you are back
会很好 你会没事的
The work fine you'll be fine
如果你回到OR时会这样做
if you do when you step back into the OR
你回家去梅雷迪思的其他事情怎么样
How's everything else you're going home to Meredith
是的
Yeh
你穿了件高领毛衣
You're wearing a turtleneck
你白大褂里穿了件高领毛衣
A turtleneck under your scrubs.
恶心死了
It's ugly.
但不及你拥抱他恶心
Not as ugly as the fact you hugged him.
-你居然拥抱他  -我听到了  做事吧
- you hugged him. - I get it. Hear you. Let's move on.
高领毛衣不舒服
Turtlenecks aren't OK.
你不舒服  你男朋友也不舒服
You're not OK, and your boyfriend's not OK.
-你男朋友没问题吧  -什么
- Is your boyfriend OK? - What?
今天做脑手术他没问题吧
To be cutting into brains today.
-他真没事了吗  -当然没事
- Is he OK to be back? - Yes. Of course.
德瑞克没事
Derek is fine.
我目睹他手术失败的  记得吗
I was there for his carnage in the OR. Remember?
今天不是普通病人
This isn't just any patient today.
是伊兹啊
This is Izzie.
乔治
George. Hey.
你怎么没去
I'm surprised you're not...
伊兹今天不是有个大会诊吗
I mean isn't there a big presentation happening with Izzie?
就在这里
Yes, there is
她怎么了?
How was she?
我不知道
I don't know
我竟然不知道她病了
I didn't even know she was sick.
克里斯蒂娜告诉了贝利  贝利才告诉了我
Bailey told me after Christina told her.
伊兹相信克里斯蒂娜
Izzie trusted Christina.
我却被蒙在鼓里
I was the very last to know.
我觉得伊兹并不是要
Well, I'm sure Izzie wasn't trying...
我不想谈这件事了
I don't even want to talk about it anymore.
我现在只想工作
What I wanna do is work.
你有病房要查吗
You have any room on your service?
-有  有三个要做髋关节置换  -谢谢
- Yeah. I have three hip replacements on ?? - Thank you.
你们三个
You three.
我知道你们来这的原因
OK. I understand why you're here.
我了解你们想帮忙
I know you wanna help.
今天我是她的住院医生
I will be the resident on her case today.
我会给她做术前准备
I will be preping her for surgery.
如果你们要进这间病房
And if you going into that hospital room today,
只能以朋友的身份
You'll do so as her friends.
伊兹需要朋友陪伴
Izzie needs her people around her.
她需要你们告诉她  一切都会好的
She needs you tell her everything will be fine.
她需要你们握着她的手
She needs you hold her hands.
她需要的是你们  不是医生  明白吗
She needs you. Not more doctors. Understood?
太好了  我们开始吧
Great. Let's get started.
如你所知  你患有转移性黑素瘤第四期
As you know, you have stage iv metastatic melanoma.
接下来的几周  会安排你
We have a lot of surgeries and a lot of procedures
做很多手术和检查
lined up for you over the next few weeks.
我们发现肿瘤已扩散至肝脏
We've seen evidence of METS on your liver
所以我和贝利医生会切除之
So one of those surgeries Dr. Bailey and I will resect them.
我们也让产科的帕克医生加入
We also lined up Dr. Parker from O.B. to
获取尽量多的健康卵子
harvest as many healthy eggs as she can
再开始放疗
before you undergo any radiation.
没错  还要考虑小孩
Right. Babies.
动手术前你想要这么做就跟我说一声
You just leave me a word before if you wanna
但今天先要去除你颞叶中的肿瘤
But our priority today is to address the temporal lobe mets on your brain.
必须尽快去除
I'm surprised we need to catch it soon.
此肿瘤会引起头痛  抽搐
This kind of thing can cause headaches and seizures.
以及严重的幻觉
and intense hallucinations.
如果我能把肿瘤除尽  幻觉就会消失
But hopefully delusion has cleared much since I can remove it all.
你们讲完了吗
Are you people done?
接下来四周  你会做三次大手术
Over the next four weeks, you're slated for three major surgeries.
七次门诊检查
Seven out-patient procedures.
这还仅仅针对已发现的肿瘤
That's just for the METS we've already found
我们可能还会发现更多
And all likelihood we will find more
这意味着  你可能会经历更多的手术
Which means we may have to cut into you more
现在起  你要有所准备
You may get used to the idea now.
我会负责你所有的放疗
I'll be adiministering all your radiation
化疗和免疫治疗
chemotherapy and immunotherapy.
治疗具有侵袭性
The treatment will be agressive.
过程不会好受  你应有所心理准备
It would be harsh. You should prepare yourself.
我会监察你的所有手术过程
I will be overseeing all your procedures,
包括今天谢博德医生将进行的手术
Including today's with Dr. Shepherd.
也就是说  现在起这间屋里每个人
Which means every surgeon in this room
都要向我汇报
now answers to me.
谢谢大家参加会诊
Welcome to the counseling, folks.
手术室见
See you in the OR.
你们别站在这儿盯着我
Seriously, don't just stand there staring at me.
我承认  我会紧张的
Well, I admit it. I can be nervours.
出去吧
Get out of here.
拯救生命去吧
Go save lives.
我们还要巡房  好吧
Yeah. We're on rounds. OK.
等会儿见
See you later.
斯隆医生  你好
Hi, Dr. Sloan.
他们是乔伊斯阿姨的侄子
These are Aunt Joice's nephews.
我的兄弟托本和卢克
These're my brothers Toben and Luke
他们今早飞过来的
They flew in early this morning.
斯隆医生是负责的医生
Dr. Sloan is doing the surgery.
抱歉  你们的阿姨病入膏肓
I'm sorry. Your aunt is very sick.
我们已无能为力
There's not much more we can do for her.
差不多该告别了
Probably time to say goodbyes.
你是说现在告别
you mean, like say our goodbyes now
还是接下来的24小时内
or some time in next 24 hours?
我是说  大概还有多少时间
I mean what kind of time frame are we talking about?
24小时  不大可能
24 hours seems unlikely.
你确定
You sure?
我一大早还要赶飞机
Because I have a flight to catch in the morning.
如果过了中午  我就赶不上了
And if I wait past noon, I can't change it.
我今晚就需要上飞机
I actually need to be on the plane tonight.
明天有董事会议
Board meeting tomorrow.
所以  你觉得她明天前能死吗
So do you think she'll die before tomorrow?
你真觉得谢博德能做斯蒂文斯的手术
You really think Shepherd's a god for Steven's surgery today?
你有其他人选吗
Did you have somebody else in mind?
考虑到谢博德近期的表现
Shepherd wouldn't be my choice
我是不会选他的
Given his recent history.
但他要动刀子的可不是我的脑袋
But hey, it's not my brain that man's handling.
-没错  -该死
- No. - Damn!
她的白细胞抗原是D3型
She's HLA type D3
必须使用氮烯咪胺
Have to hit her with the DTIC
以及IO-2
and high dose IO-2 instead.
IO-2毒性很高
IO 2. That's pretty toxic.
跟我想的一样糟
It's about as bad as I guess.
你现在就要去告诉伊兹吗
You're gonna tell Izzie this right now?
我是她的肿瘤医生
I am her oncologist
研究表明在手术前告诉病人坏消息
Study show that giving patients bad news right before surgery
手术中的并发症几率会增高
can drastically increase their chances of complications on the table.
今天说还是明天说  坏消息还是坏消息
Today or tomorrow, the news is the same.
而现在我有空
And right now, I have time.
你来吗
You coming?
伊兹现在正在放射科
I believe Izzie is down in radiology now.
好吧  我们可以等一小时后再说
Fine. We can wait an hour.
克莱夫  我看了伊兹近期的核磁共振成像
Karev, I just reviewed Izzie's most recent MRI.
看来从上次以来  肿瘤没有扩散
Doesn't look the tumor's grown since her last cancer.
这是好消息
That's good news.
在给伊兹解释手术前
Do you have any questions or concerns you'd like to discuss with me
你还有什么问题或担忧吗
before we brief Izzie.
这次别再把额叶切了就行
Just try keeping her frontal lobe inside her skull this time.
早上好  伊兹
Good morning, Izzie.
你进来吗
You come?
不了  我还有个老太太的病例要处理
No. I'm on this old lady. So
你确定  这要不了多久
Are you sure? This'll only take a minute.
我真得走了
I gotta go. Really.
她没事吧
She's doing OK?
她是这么说的
Yeah. Well, she said she is.
你信吗
Do you believe her?
不信
No. Not really.
快看
Oh. Heads up.
主任  你呼我
Chief. You paged me?
克莱夫  对  是我呼的你
Oh, Karev. Yes, I did.
我们准备获取卵子
I should know we're gonna be harvesting eggs
斯蒂文斯的
from Stevens.
我知道你们俩有那种关系
Who I believe is someone you're having relation with.
-主任  -冰冻卵子受精后
- Chief. - Frozen eggs have a better survival rate
存活率更高
went they're fertilized.
受精
fertilized.
我知道你需要时间
I know this is a lot to digest.
慢慢来
So take some time.
考虑一下
Think about it.
如果你决定这就是某人想要的
If you decide this is somebody might want to consider
把杯子给我
Just give me the cup.
克莱夫  你得先跟伊兹谈谈
Karev. You need to speak to Stevens.
把杯子给我
Just give me the cup.
什么情况
What do you hear?
摩托车驾驶失控
Motorcycle lost control.
没戴头盔  头部严重受伤
No helmet. Massive head trauma.
生命体征很弱
Lots of vital signs unmoved.
-谢博德  你能回来真好  -谢谢
- Good to have you back, Shepherd. - Thanks.
快来
Come on.
亨特  听见没
Hunt. You hear me?
欧文
Owen.
史文德毫无远见
Swender has no vision.
他今早掐着你的脖子
He grabbed his hands on your throat this morning.
你却假装什么都没发生
You pretending like nothing happened?
你关心伊兹就行了
Just focus on Izzie.
亨特差点掐死你了
Hunt literally tried to kill you.
他还没从伊拉克战争的阴影中走出来
He's barely back form Iraq.
很明显他有问题
It's obvious he has issues.
这并不意味着你一定要陪着他
That doesn't mean you have to stand by.
如果他是心脏病发或者中风  或是断了腿
So like if he had a heart attack or stroke or lost a leg
你就会袖手旁观
Would, would you walk away?
亨特这样我还离弃他  难道可以接受吗
So how is it anymore acceptable that I walk away from this?
他受伤了  战争所伤  梅瑞狄斯
He's wounded. He's war wounds. Meredith.
这不是负伤开车
It's not cut and drive.
没你想的那么糟
And it is not as bad as you think it is.
让开
Clear.
该是时候了
This might be it.
希望上帝听到你说的话
From your lips to God's ears.
充电360伏  让开
Charge to 360. Clear.
上帝真是对她好啊
Oh, for the love of god.
你知道有多少人此刻正在医院祈祷
Hey, you know how many people are in this hospital right now
他们所爱的人能够活下来
Waiting, hoping that their loved one might actually live?
-你们这帮没人性的  -我们有
You're a bunch of vultures. but we're not.
三年前乔伊斯阿姨就被宣判只剩一个月生命了
Aunt joyce was given one month to live three years ago.
我们火速赶到
And we were crushed,
在她的床边握着她的手一连好几周
And we held her hand at her bedside for weeks,
流着泪跟她告别
And we said our tearful good-byes,
接着
And then...
她病情稳定了
She stabilized.
出院后一个月她又进去了
She's been in and out of the hospital once a month.
每次我们都跳上飞机  来坐在她的床边
Each time, we jump on a plane, sit by her bed,
一次次跟她含泪告别
Say our good-byes all over again,
而每一次  她都重新好过来
And each time, she winds up getting better.
我们希望她走的时候能够陪在她身边
We want to be here when she goes.
我们真的希望可以  但是
We--we really do, but...
我们已经飞了很多次了
It's a lot of flying around the country.
她准备好了  我们也是
She's ready. we're all ready.
是时候了
It's time.
我明天还要开董事长会
And I've got a board meeting tomorrow.
重量级的
Big one.
目前的调查测试显示了
You know, they're doing tests
创伤后心理失调症病人的脑部变化
That show altered brain anatomy in patients with p.t.s.d.
很快就能发现
They're actually getting close to understanding
心理创伤带来生理损伤
The physical side of the psychological trauma.
核磁共振结果很令人震惊
It's amazing what you can see with an m.r.i.
关于昨晚  梅丽狄斯怎么跟你说的
What did meredith tell you about last night?
-她怎么说  -过去的创伤压力对你有损伤  欧文
What did she say? post-traumatic stress is a real injury, owen.
能治好的
It can be healed.
这里设备齐全  有诊疗中心 有心理治疗
There are resources-- vet centers, therapy.
你不该逞强自己解决
You shouldn't try and handle this on your own.
我完好无损的回来  有手有脚
I came back in one piece. I have both arms, both legs.
大部分人回来后都有心理阴影
Lots of guys came back with real injuries.
如果最糟糕的只是我晚上狂做噩梦
If the worst I have is a couple nightmares or--
-短暂的寒冷  -你是说昨晚也是?
-freezing for a moment.  - is that what happened last night?
你有短暂的寒冷?
You had a freezing moment?
只要你愿意  我会帮你的
If you want, I can help.
是吗  我可不是那个需要帮忙的人
Oh, yeah? I'm not the one who needs help around here.
我可不是那个切掉一个女人的半个脑袋
I'm not the one who cut out half a woman's brain
然后逃之夭夭的人
Then ran off to hide.
我可不是被半个医院的人在背后
I'm not the one who half this hospital is talking about
窃窃私语的人
Behind their back.
所以说  你少担心我了
So maybe you should spend a little less time
还有
Worrying about me, and, you know,
去照照镜子吧  明白?
Just take a look in the mirror, all right?
克莱夫
Karev.
我来看看  看你能不能...
Just checking in, see how your can--
看你的进展如何
See how you'reoing.
如果你不在隔壁偷听的话
I'd be doing better if you weren't
我会做得更好些
On the other side of the door listening.
好的  好的  抱歉
Uh, right, right. sorry.
快走啊
I said go away.
你没锁门  太粗心了
You left the door unlocked. that's bold.
主任把你关在这儿
The chief send you in here?
-不是  -我自愿来看看  也许你需要人说说话
Nope. I offered to come in, in case you needed to talk.
你是说要帮助我吗?
You think talking will help?
你认为装满精子的纸杯
You think a dixie cup full of my swimmers
会让一切顺利?
Will make everything okay?
一团糟  这根本就是乱来
It's crap. this is crap.
不能再把大家的脑子搞的乱糟糟的
You just can't go messing with people's heads like that.
我是说  即使在冷冻的情况下
I mean, even if she freezes the embryos,
你觉得  你觉得我们有机会用他们吗
You think--you think we'll get a chance to use them?
你觉得她还会这里
You think she'll still be here?
你觉得她能挺过来吗
You think she'll survive all this?
你觉得...
Do you think...
我想
I think...
她告诉我
She t-told me--
她说见到了鬼  明白吗
She told me she was seeing a ghost, okay?
我这辈子对这种事见怪不怪
And I'm so used to all the crazy chicks in my life
我甚至没
That I didn't even...
我是个医生
I'm a doctor.
一个医生
A doctor!
我都没想到
And I didn't even think to...
现在她
And now she's...
这
This is...
不该这样
This is wrong.
不该这样的
This isn't how it's supposed to happen.
我明白
I know.
一团糟  我知道
It's crap. I know.
我讨厌这样
I hate this.
我知道
I know.
这不是
This isn't...
这不是  不是我们期待...
This isn't how we... how we were supp--
我不想这么做
This isn't how I wanted to do this.
我跟伊兹没想过  用这种方法有一个孩子
This isn't how Izzie and I were supposed to make a baby.
我一整天没见到你
I haven't seen you all day.
如果我没醒过来怎么办
What if I hadn't woken up?
我都不记得发生了什么  什么都没有
I can't even remember what happened. it's gone.
什么都不记得  没办法
I have no memory, no--no way to...
我永远都不会伤害你的  永远
I would never hurt you, ever.
可我却做了
But I did.
我的手
My hands just...
我是说  要是
I mean, how could--
我自己的双手怎么能够...
How could my own two hands be capable...
-我不能这么做  克里斯蒂娜  -可是你确实醒过来了
-I can't do this. cristina -but you did wake up.
我们不能再见面了
We need to stop seeing each other.
不能再见面  为什么
We have to stop seeing each other. why?
-克里斯蒂娜  我几乎  -几乎什么
Cristina, I almost-- almost what?
我跟你说过  我知道自己的极限
I told you, I know my limits.
让我来做决定
Let me decide what I can handle.
好的  站着别动
Oh, good. stand right there.
让我看看  我不知道需要多长时间
Let me see. I never know how long to make these.
我喜欢这颜色  送给克莱夫的吗
I like the color. who's it for, karev? unh-un
今天没怎么看到他
Haven't seen much of him today.
他在工作  他们都在工作
He's working. they're all working.
我让他们去工作  他们都是医生
I told them to go work. they're doctors.
他们的病人
Their patients shouldn't suffer
不该因为我得了癌症而受苦
Just because I have things growing on my organs.
我今天下午有个结肠切除术
I have a colectomy this afternoon.
如果你是协助我的住院医生
If you were the resident assisting me,
我会让你分离盲肠  怎么分离
And I were to say to you, "divide the cecum,"  What would you use?
贝利医生  我不是你的协助医生
dr. bailey, I'm not assisting you,
你也没让我分离盲肠
And you're not gonna ask me to divide the cecum.
可我不会让你技术生疏的
But I'm not gonna let you get rusty.
从现在开始的一年内  你要学会处理这些事情
A year from now, you need to be able to do this stuff.
你要教会你的住院医生如何做这些
You need to be able to teach your residents how to do it.
你真的认为一年内我能成为住院医生
You really think I'm gonna be here a year from now?
是的
Yes, I do.
现在  我打开右下腹
So... I have exposed the right lower quadrant,
你会用什么来分开盲肠
And you are dividing the cecum with...
钳子
Forceps.
避开蛛网膜抬升
I lift free from the arachnoid.
定位缝合线
Tacking sutures.
扁针
Patties.
吸
Suction.
继续多练吧
lets training a lot
给你杯子  都装满了
Here's your cup, all filled up.
克莱夫  我正吃东西呢
I'm eating here, karev.
没关系  我洗过手了
It's fine. I washed my hands.
你跟伊兹谈过了吗
did you talk to Izzie about this yet?
考虑到你跟伊兹今天
Considering you two are basically
理论上会有个孩子
Conceiving a child together today,
你不觉得应该跟她谈谈吗
Don't you think you should talk with her about this?
听着  你说过她需要我的捐献
Look, you said she needed my... contribution.
这就是我的捐献  随便你
Here's my contribution. whatever.
嘿  伊兹怎么样了
Hey, how's Izzie?
我不清楚
I don't know.
-伊兹怎么样了  -为什么问我
-How's Izzie? -why?
你见过她吗
Have you been to see her?
没有  我一整天都跟史文得在工作
no, I've been working with swender all day.
怎么了
What?
-你去见过伊兹吗  -没有  你们呢
-Have you been to see Izzie? -no. haven't you?
你一天就织好了
You finished that thing in one day?
有点闲
Had some free time.
是非常闲
I've had a lot of free time.
没人来看你吗
Nobody came up to visit?
没事
It's okay.
如果我是他们
If I were them,
我也不愿意呆在这屋子里
I wouldn't want to step foot in this room either.
你没必要一直观察我的情况  明白吗
You don't have to keep checking up on me, you know?
我必须这么做
I do have to.
必须在上手术台之前给你输这个
I have to start you on this before your surgery.
是啊  手术
Right. surgery.
我还想告诉你
Well, and I wanted to tell you
今天下午有多少个手术要做
How my surgery went this afternoon.
克隆男孩
Colon guy.
对  结肠切除术做的不错
Yeah. now the colectomy went great.
可我在现场  有点问题
But I was in there, and I see a mass.
你开玩笑吧  大问题吗
You're kidding. was it a big mass?
挺大的  拳头的大小有点问题
It was big enough, about the size of a fist.
开始有点灼烧感
This is going to burn a little at first,
一会就会好的
But, uh, just for a few seconds.
所以在我们切除并接合肠子之前
So we had to mobilize the s.m.a.
我们得激活抗平滑肌抗体
Before we could resect the thing and reconnect the bowel.
我曾希望伊兹·斯蒂文斯死
I wished Izzie stevens would die.
我恨不得她死几百次
I wished her dead every day of every week
不知道有多久了
For I don't even know how long.
每天早晨醒来  都希望伊兹·斯蒂文斯死
I woke up every morning wishing Izzie stevens would die.
可是现在
And now...
什么样的人才会盼着别人死
What kind of person wishes someone would die?
什么样的医生
What kind of doctor wishes
知道事情怎么发展
knowing how things happen,
什么...
What ...
什么样...
What kind of...
医生会希望...
doctor wishes...
你现在是在祈祷  希望伊兹死吗
Are you in here right now praying for Izzie to die?
不是
No.
我为她祈祷  希望她能活着
I'm praying for her to live.
让开
Clear.
知道吗  为什么不在外面等呢
You know what? why don't you all wait outside?
-如果她...你会通知我们吗  -会的  会通知你们的
-Will you let us know if she-- yeah, yeah, I'll let you know.
杂种
Bastards.
推一单位肾上腺素 360伏  让开
Push 1 epi. charge to 360. clear.
挺住啊  乔伊斯  老太婆
come on, joyce, you old bag.
别让他们得逞
Don't give 'em the satisfaction.
再充电  让开
Charge again. clear.
我是克莱夫医生
I'm dr. karev.
你是个斗士  知道吗
You're a fighter, you know that?
你今天非常努力
You worked hard today.
她需要休息
She needs some rest.
去告诉家人  确保他们不会进来
Um, see the family, make sure they don't come back in here.
让她离开那些爱她的人好好休息下
Give her a break from all the love.
不是的
No.
他们没耐心了
They're impatient.
已经拖了很久了
It's been a long time.
可是每一次他们都会过来
But they always come.
他们是我的亲人
They're my people.
亲人给你勇气
People keep you going.
有亲人比老无所依强
People are better than no people.
现在不是时候  他正在洗手上台
Uh, it's not a good time. he's still scrubbing in.
我知道  只是  他该戴着这个
I know. it's just, uh, he should wear this.
他的渡轮手术帽  他喜欢渡轮
It's his ferry boat scrub cap. he loves ferry boats.
梅丽狄斯
Meredith.
你在干嘛  你还得再消一次毒
What are you doing? you're gonna have to rescrub.
我没准备好
I'm not ready.
你准备好了
Yes, you are.
你想要
You want
我要知道  你还想跟我在一起
I need to know that at least I have you.
不管会发生什么  我需要知道
No matter what happens in there, I need to know.
-你要答应我  我需要答案  -我不能答应你
-I need you to say yes. I need to know. -I can't say yes,
我不能保证如果伊兹死了
Not if agreeing to be with you forever
还能跟你永远在一起
Will make it okay if Izzie dies.
我不能答应
I can't say yes.
我在这里
I'm here
我哪都不去
I not going any where
我爱你
I love you
你一定能成功
And you can do this.
一定能成功  我知道你可以的
You can do this. I know you can.
伊兹
Izzie...
斯蒂文斯医生  回头见
I'll see you soon, dr. stevens.
希望如此
I hope so.
很快就知道了
Know so.
贝利医生  如果发生什么意外
Dr. bailey, if something goes wrong--
不会的
They won't.
那条围巾
The scarf...
是织给你的
I made it for you.
救死扶伤的动人夜晚
Beautiful night to save lives.
开始吧
Let's get started.
好吧  我知道我为什么没去
Okay, so I get why I haven't been camped out
伊兹床边握着她的手
At Izzie's bedside holding her hand today,
-可是  -我不想谈这个
But-- I'm not talking about this.
为什么不
Why not?
也许这就是事实  我问了伊兹几百遍
Maybe it's the fact that I asked Izzie a hundred times
出什么事了
What was wrong,
她把我当透明的
And she just ignored me.
而事实是  当她需要帮助的时候
And then there's the fact that when she actually needed help,
她
She turn--
她在所有人里  告诉了克里斯蒂娜
She trusted cristina, of all people.
现在情况是  她作为你最好的朋友
And then there's the fact that she's your best friend
可能会死在你面前
And she might die on you.
这也是事实
There's also that.
别这样
Come on.
我们去等伊兹出来
We are going to go wait for Izzie.
快点
Come on.
乔治  你是我前夫  跟她搞外遇
George, you were my husband and you slept with her.
因为你我才盼着她死
You are the reason that I wished her dead.
你欠我的
You owe me this.
听着  你可以想办法骗你自己
Look, you can lie to yourself all you want,
可我了解你
But I know you.
我曾经爱过你
I loved you once.
我明白你很在意她的死活
And I know that you care if she lives or dies.
手术开始了
Surgery started.
-嘿  手术开始了吗  -开始了
-Hey, have they started the surgery?-Yeah.
格蕾医生  我们想知道
dr. grey, we were wondering,
斯蒂文斯医生的手术开始了吗
Did dr. stevens' surgery start yet or--
走开  不要在手术室的走廊里闲逛
Keep it moving. no loitering in the o.r. hallway.
-这是规定  -要是他们想留下  就留下吧
-That's the rule. -if they want to stay, let 'em stay.
有人守着比没人强
People are better than no people.
好吧  夹钳
Okay, clamp.
好的  我准备  等一下
All right, I'm ready to, uh--no.
好了
Yes, okay.
我准备刺激颞浅动脉了
I'm ready to buzz the superficial temporal artery.
-隆起缝合线  -不要着急  慢慢来
-Tenting sutures. -there's no rush. take your time.
-所有的人都支持你  -你确定那能撑住
-Everyone here is on your side. a-re you sure that's gonna hold,
-脆弱的疤痕组织吗  -swender医生
What, with all that friable scar tissue? dr. swender.
事实上我上个月见谢博特医生
Uh, actually I saw dr. shepherd
做过三次不同的穿颅术
Do three different craniotomies last month,
每一次都比这个疤痕组织翻倍脆弱
Each with easily double the amount of friable tissue.
绝对撑得住
They held just fine.
隆起缝合线
Next tenting suture, please.
让开
Clear.
再推一单位肾上腺素  再充电
push another epi. charge again.
挺住啊  沃林顿夫人  让开
Come on, mrs. wallington. clear.
非常抱歉
Uh, i-i'm so sorry.
没有反应  我们尽全力了
She's not responding. we've done everything we can.
她  她死了
So... she's gone.
谢谢你  你做的很好了
Thank you. you did a wonderful job.
耍我呢吧
Are you kidding me?
天哪  没完没了了
Oh, god. this is never gonna end.
不是的  她死了
No, no, she--she's gone.
真的死了  真的
She's really gone. it's really gone.
只是  她的起搏器  还在工作
It's--it's, um, it's her pacemaker. it's still firing,
看起来好像还有心跳
So it makes it seem like there's a heartbeat,
可是她已经死了
But she's gone.
还有心跳
Just... with a heartbeat.
你确定她死了吗  小姐
Are you sure she's dead, young lady?
我是实习生  没权在这种情况下
I--i'm an intern. I'm not authorized to call time of death
宣布死亡
In a situation like this.
那我  我去叫我的上级
So i--i'm gonna get my superior.
请原谅  我  我很快就回来  原谅
Excuse me. I'll-- I'll be right back. excuse me.
-我在担心你  -得了  梅丽狄斯
-I'm worried about you. o-h, meredith--
-差点窒息  你明白吗  -住口
-Choking. you know what? -stop.
-不能这样  -别问了行吗
-It's unacceptable. -will you back off?
掐你的脖子
Hands around the neck.
在你面前把戒指扔了
Ring thrown in your face.
这可以让起搏器停止工作
This will shut the pacemaker down.
死亡时间晚上10点40分
Time of death--2240.
就这样了  她正式死亡
There you go. she's officially dead.
你可以去赶飞机了  参加你的董事会议
You can catch your plane and get to your board meeting.
你们  可以走了
You can--you can leave.
事实上
Actually...
我们能再待会吗
Could we stay a little while longer?
你们在外面干什么呢
What are you all doing out here?
等伊兹出来  主任
Waiting for Izzie, sir.
我们在等
We're waiting.
你害怕了
You're scared.
我也很怕
I'm scared, too.
该死
Damn it.
一些大脑外侧裂血管
Some of the sylvian vessels
缠绕在肿瘤外面
Have wrapped around the tumor capsule.
潘二氏4号手术刀
Penfield 4, please.
你确定吗  不用蛛网膜刀
Really? instead of the arachnoid knife?
确定  不用蛛网膜刀
Yes, instead of the arachnoid knife,
因为潘二氏4号手术刀可以让我
Because the penfield 4 will let me
移开遮挡视线的动脉
Slide the arteries around the met.
我需要分开它们
I need to dissect it free
这样就可以去除肿瘤
So that I can debulk the tumors,
彻底去除我病人的肿瘤
Avoiding unnecessary trauma to my patient.
所以我确定  用penfield 4
So yes, penfield 4, please.
重要器官都稳定吗
Were her vitals stable the entire time?
颅内压稳定吗
Were there any spikes in her intracranial pressure?
肿瘤切除干净了吗
Is there any residual tumor?
谢博特切除了所有的肿瘤
Shepherd was able to resect all of the tumor.
一小时后她会进监护病房
She'll be in the pacu for about an hour.
她挺过来了
She's fine.
你的朋友没事  不该谢你们任何一个人
Your friend is just fine, no thanks to any of you.
明天  表现好些
Tomorrow, do better.
手术进行的很顺利
The surgery went well today.
你和梅丽狄斯
Shouldn't you and meredith
要出去庆祝吗
Be out celebrating or something?
她拒绝了我  两次
She turned me down, twice.
她说她明白
She says she understands,
在树林里发生的一切  她原谅了我
She forgives me for what happened in the woods,
你展现了消极的一面
So you showed her your dark side?
梅丽狄斯不是一个
Meredith never struck me as a woman
害怕消极的女人
Who was afraid of the dark.
我不明白
I don't know.
你知道那是梅丽狄斯的主意吗
Do you know it was meredith's idea
问伊兹是不是想要个孩子
To ask Izzie if she wanted to harvest her eggs,
这样伊兹将来就会有一个期望
So Izzie could have a chance at the future she wanted?
那是关于将来  德瑞克
The future, derek.
她相信你今天能成功
She was confident you'd succeed today.
梅丽狄斯相信你
Meredith believes in you.
伊兹  我在这
I'm here, Izzie.
就在你身边
I'm right here.
伊兹的手术很成功
Izzie's surgery went well.
太好了  真好
Good. that's good.
我希望事情本可以...
I wish things were...
他们就可以
That they could be...
我们就能
That we could be...
我也是
Me, too.
我能  我能抱抱你吗
Can i--can I hold you?
等一下  等等  你不能坐这个电梯
Wait. uh, wait. no. y-you can't take that one.
-为什么    -我说了不能
-Why not?  - I said don't take it.
我想坐哪个电梯就坐哪个
I will take the elevator I want to take.
好吧  进去吧
Well, go on.
嘿  快进来
Hey. come on in.
这是卡蒂·布莱斯的CT
This is the c.t. for katie bryce--
16岁  女性
16-year-old female,
蛛网膜下动脉瘤
Subarachnoid aneurysm.
韵律操的时候摔了  我记得
From a fall during rhythmic gymnastics. I remember.
那是我们第一次一起做的手术
It was the first surgery we ever scrubbed in together on,
我们第一次救人
Our first save.
这是一个棘手的大脑胞囊  我们成功了
Right here is a cerebral cyst. tough save, but we did it.
手术后我在楼梯井吻了你
I kissed you in the stairwell after the surgery.
这个是贝利医生
And this right here is where dr. bailey
把你踢出手术  因为她发现我们
Kicked you out of the surgery because she caught us
一起回家
In your driveway in my car.
这里是一次7小时的颅骨切开术
And right here--this is a 7-hour craniotomy,
整个过程中你都拿着夹钳  没有退缩
And you held the clamp the entire time, never flinched.
从那时起我知道  你会是个了不起的医生
That's when I knew you were gonna be an incredible surgeon.
这是贝斯·门罗
And beth monroe,
我们临床试演的幸存者
Who made our clinical trial a success by surviving.
你劝我给她试验的
You talked me into putting her under.
那时起我知道我离不开你
That's when I knew I needed you.
这是今天的
And this is today.
伊兹·斯蒂文斯的术后脑CT
Post-op head c.t. of Izzie stevens.
看见没
You see that?
肿瘤没了
Tumor free...
都是因为你
Because of you.
你让我走进了手术室
You got me into the o.r.
如果有什么困难  你从不驻足
If there's a crisis, you don't freeze.
而是迎头向前
You move forward.
你让我们能够继续前进
You get the rest of us to move forward,
因为你遭遇困境  努力走出困境
Because you've seen worse, you've survived worse.
你知道我们一定可以在一起
And you know we'll survive, too.
你说你是  消极和扭曲的
You say you're all... dark and twisty,
可那不是缺点
But that's not a flaw.
是一种力量
It's a strength.
造就了你
It makes you who you are.
我不会单膝跪下
I'm not gonna get down on one knee.
也不会问你是否愿意
I'm not gonna ask a question.
我爱你  梅丽狄斯·格蕾
I love you, meredith grey.
我想与你共度余生
And I want to spend the rest of my life with you.
我愿意与你共度余生
我不认为
I don't think...
我还是承受不了
I can't handle it after all.
什么  什么意思
What? what do you mean?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
I'm so, so sorry.
可是我躺在你的臂弯
But I'm lying here in your arms...
却不敢入睡
And I'm afraid to fall asleep.
与困难无关
Doesn't matter how tough we are...
我  我想为之前的事情道歉
I... I wanted to apologize for earlier.
我说的那些  太过分了
What I said was... it was out of line.
已经过去了
It's already forgotten.
感谢你的帮助
Thank you for doing this.
创伤总会留下伤疤
Trauma always leaves a scar.
我订婚了
I'm engaged.
我跟欧文分手了
I broke up with owen.
跟随我们回家
It follows us home...
改变我们的生活
It changes our liv...
今天我为你捐献了镜子
I snooched into a cup for you today.
谢谢
Um... thank you
创伤让人陷入困境
Trauma messes everybody up.
也许正是因为如此
But maybe that's the point.
所有的伤痛  恐惧和烂摊子
All the pain and the fear and the crap...
经历这一切
Maybe going through all of that
是我们前进的动力
Is what keeps us moving forward.
激励我们
It's what pushes us.
也许在我们加速前进之前
Maybe we have to get a little messed up
应该混乱点
Before we can step up